A Finding Aid to the Organization of Independent Artists Records, circa 1970s-circa 2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.orgainda
Archives of American Art
Organization of Independent Artists records
circa 1970s-circa 2003
AAA.orgainda
Archives of American Art
28.4 Linear feet
The Organization of Independent Artists records measure 28.4 linear feet and date from circa 1970s to circa 2003. The records include administrative records, correspondence, exhibition and installation files, artists’ files, financial and legal records, printed material, seven scrapbooks, and photographs.
Organization of Independent Artists.
Biographical/Historical note
The Organization of Independent Artists (OIA) is a non-profit arts organization founded in 1976 by Warren Tanner, Arnold Wechsler, and Renee Meyer. The organization's mission is to sponsor artist-curated group shows and enable exhibitions of emerging and mid-career artists in public spaces throughout the New York City area outside of the usual commercial and alternative gallery venues.
OIA activities have included organizing public space exhibitions and displays of artwork, publishing a quarterly newsletter, maintaining a slide registry of artists' work and extensive artists' mailing lists, and arranging studio tours. The Arts in Public Spaces Program was initiated in 1976 with the passage of the Public Buildings Cooperative Usage Act, a public law that encourages the use of public space in federal buildings for cultural and educational activities. Participating professional artists have included Thornton Willis, Joan Thorne, Vincent Longo, Mimi Gross Grooms, Hannah Wilke, Nancy Spero, Richard Mock, and Joyce Kozloff, among others. By 1986, OIA had facilitated the display of more than 5,000 works of art in forty public exhibition sites, which included courthouses, libraries, building lobbies, public parks, college campuses, and hospital grounds in all five boroughs of New York City, and over 2,000 artists had participated it its Art in Public Spaces program.
Other exhibition collaborations have included Cork Gallery at Lincoln Center, General Services Administration, John F. Kennedy Airport, Long Island University in Brooklyn, Longwood Arts Center in the Bronx, New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, Port Authority Bus Terminal, Queens Museum in Flushing Meadow Park, Snug Harbor Cultural Center on Staten Island, U.S. Federal Courthouse in Brooklyn, and the grounds of the South Beach Psychiatric Center on Staten Island. Since 1979, the annual OIA Sculpture Garden at the Manhattan Psychiatric Center on Ward’s Island has afforded hundreds of artists the opportunity to construct and install large-scale outdoor work in an urban environment, and many artists have received individual commissions, one-person shows, and have sold art work as a direct result of their participation.
Other OIA exhibition programming has resulted in ten to twelve artist-curated shows per year, and has assisted the artist-curator by identifying and negotiating exhibition locations, as well as producing announcement cards and posters, providing insurance, hosting the artists’ reception, advising and assisting with publicity, and undergoing extensive fundraising for artists’ and curators’ fees.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Organization of Independent Artists records were donated in 2003 by the organization via Geraldine Cosentino, Director.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives’ Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Scope and Contents note
The Organization of Independent Artists records measure 28.4 linear feet and date from circa 1970s to circa 2003. The records include administrative records, correspondence, exhibition and installation files, artists’ files, financial and legal records, printed material, seven scrapbooks, and photographs.
Administrative records include scattered files about the board of directors/trustees, the advisory board, membership, events, gallery rental space, loans, other organizations, and the general history of the OIA. Also found are exhibitions lists, schedules, and proposals, as well as drafts of OIA printed materials. Correspondence with artists, board members, donors, financial institutions, and other organizations is found in many of the files.
Exhibition and installation files comprise the bulk of the records and include files for the Annual OIA Salon Show, the OIA Sculpture Garden assembled annually on the grounds of the Manhattan Psychiatric Center on Ward’s Island, several shows of Selections from the Slide Files, as well as numerous other group exhibitions and installations.
The artists' files contain a variety of materials, including photographs, and are found for Hera, Tom Klem, Mary Shaffer and a few others. Financial and legal records document the organization’s many grant applications, invoices and bills paid, tax materials, and legal issues. Printed materials include OIA newsletters, show announcements and brochures, and exhibition materials and clippings. There is one clippings scrapbook and six scrapbooks of exhibition materials. Photographs depict exhibitions and installations as well as artwork; additional photographs of exhibitions are also filed with the exhibition files.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Administrative Records, circa 1976-2002 (3.5 linear feet; Boxes 1-4)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1976-2002 (0.8 linear feet; Boxes 4-5)
Series 3: Exhibition and Installation Files, circa 1970s-circa 2003 (13 linear feet; Boxes 5-18)
Series 4: Artists' Files, circa 1980s-circa 1990s (0.2 linear feet; Box 18)
Series 5: Financial and Legal Records, circa 1970s-circa 2002 (6.9 linear feet; Boxes 18-25, 29)
Series 6: Printed Material, circa 1970s-circa 2002 (3.1 linear feet; Boxes 25-29, OV30)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, circa 1977-2000 (0.7 linear feet; Box 28)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1980s-circa 1990s (0.2 linear feet; Box 28-29)
Hera, 1940-; Klem, Tom; Shaffer, Mary; Art galleries, Cooperative--New York (State)--New York; Art patronage; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Administrative Records, circa 1976-2002; Series 1; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-4
  Arrangement note
  Files are arranged by topic, activity, or name of event.
  Scope and Contents note
  Administrative records include board of directors’ materials and membership files, OIA event materials and information, art council and art organization files, general administrative records, committee materials, history and founding documents, a few general exhibition planning files, and artist and project contracts. Also found are drafts of OIA printed material, such as brochures, newsletters, and calendars, as well as intern files, requests for shows, supplies, and information for a proposed 11th anniversary book. Information files and applications for the OIA Warren Tanner Memorial Art Fund are also included here.
  - Administrative Notes, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Board Directory, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Around the Coyote (ATC), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Artist Contracts, Drafts, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Artists Lists, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art and Business Council, Inc., 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Battery Park City Authority, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, circa 1980s-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-15)
  - Board of Trustees, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brochure Drafts, circa 1983-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas, circa 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Calendars, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Censorship, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - C. E. T. A., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Consultants, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Events, Annual Benefit Art Raffle, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23-51)
  - Events, "Rubin's Roast", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Events, Tenth Anniversary Benefit, circa 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Committee, circa 1981-circa 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Lists, circa 1977-circa 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Proposals, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Exhibition Schedule and Drafts, circa 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Space, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Film Project Proposals, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Financial Management Center, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fran Nicosia, Program Director, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gallery Rental Space, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Administrative Records, circa 1970s-2002 (Box 2, Folder 14-29)
  - GSA Forms, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - History of OIA, circa 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 31-39)
  - Interns, circa 1983-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Liquor Donations, circa 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Loan Forms, circa 1980s-circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Members, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Membership, circa 1980s-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8-12)
  - National Association of Artists Organizations, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter Drafts, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts, circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - New York State Arts and Cultural Coalition, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - OIA 11th Anniversary Book, circa 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17-21)
  - Prints, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Program Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Project Contracts, circa 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Requests for OIA Shows, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Requests for Proposals, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Spaces Guide, DCA, circa 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Supplies, circa 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Stationery, OIA, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Visitors to View Slide Files, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Warren Tanner Memorial Art Fund, 1981-1997 (Box 3, Folder 32-39)
  - Warren Tanner Memorial Art Fund, circa 1985-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1-17)
- Correspondence, circa 1976-2002; Series 2; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Correspondence is arranged by subject/name according to the organization's original order.
  Scattered correspondence is with other arts organizations and prospective installation organizations, artists, OIA board of directors, the Cultural Council Foundation, and the General Services Administration. Correspondence concerns exhibitions, donations, financial and fundraising matters, press and publicity, and the search for a permanent office space for the organization.
  - Artists, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Board Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cultural Council Foundation, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Donation Letters, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Financial Correspondence, circa 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Fundraising Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, circa 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 26-33)
  - General Correspondence, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1-8)
  - GSA, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Phone Drive Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Press Story Solicitations, 1983-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Search for OIA Office, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Exhibition and Installation Files, circa 1970s-circa 2003; Series 3; 13 Linear feet Boxes 5-18
  Exhibition and installation files include photographs and slides, exhibition announcement cards, posters, press releases, brochures, catalogs, correspondence, and price lists, as well as three guest books for various exhibitions. Among the many exhibitions and installations represented within the files are the OIA China Project (1981), Drawing on Dance (1982), Intuition and the Block Print (1984), The Ways of Wood (1984), Hanging Loose (1984), JFK Airport Project (1990), Maps and Madness (1991), Eye on Art (1992, 1993), and many others. Also included are the many OIA Sculpture Garden installations on the grounds of the Manhattan Psychiatric Center on Ward's Island, OIA Salon Shows, OIA Selections from the Slide Files, and OIA Critics' Choice shows.
  - Guest Books, Various Exhibitions, circa 1992-2002 (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
  - Ward's Island Sculpture Library/Park: Part I (1976), circa 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Art in Public Spaces (1977) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Exhibit A (1977) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Art Bank Program and Exhibitions (1977) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Exhibit at the United States Court House (1977) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 6 Artists View Development (1978) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Arte Fiera (1978) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Arts Court the Law (1978) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - CETA - OIA Outdoor Sculpture Exhibition (1978) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Color - Small Works in Color (1978) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dissonance and Harmony: Works by 26 Artists (1978) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Group Art Exhibition (1978) (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Group Show of 18 Artists (1978-1979), circa 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Living Buildings (1978) (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Personal Visions: Places Spaces (1978) (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Six Painters (1978) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sorcerer's Apprentice Machine Assisted Art (1978) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 5 Painters (1979), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Group Exhibition (1979) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Outgrowth/ Battery Park (1979), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Painterly Abstraction (1979) (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Photo Show (1979) (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Ward's Island Sculpture Garden (1979), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
  - Ward's Island Studio Housing - WISH (1979) (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - A, E, I, O, U, and Sometimes Why (1980) (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Balance: Sculpture at Foley Square (1980) (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Geometric Abstraction (1980) (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Who Am I? A Self-Portrait Show (1980), circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Art in Public Spaces (1981-1982) (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Artists Who Make Prints (1981) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Chamber Street Artists: performing/visual (1981) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Contemporary Expression (1981) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Every Picture Tells a Story (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - OIA China Project (1981), circa 1980s-circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5-8)
  - On and Off the Wall: 8 Artists from Independent Studios One (1981) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Running (1981) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Staten Island Artists in Manhattan (1981) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Various Places: 16 Artists, 16 Viewpoints (1981) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Vietnam Experience (1981), 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ward's Island Outdoor Sculpture Library (1981), circa 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 14-23)
  - Benefit Exhibition (1982), circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Burn Your Bridges (1982), 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Celebration (1982) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Drawing on Dance (1982) (Box 6, Folder 30-35)
  - Figures - OIA at Green Space (1982) (Box 6, Folder 36-38)
  - Four Artists and a Writer at Federal Hall (1982) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Green Space Gallery Shows (circa 1982) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Invites Ten to Birdhouse (1982) (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - New York Artists in Education (1982), circa 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - New York Artists Who Teach (1982) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Personal Iconography (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Space Within/ Without (1982), circa 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ward's Island Sculpture Garden (1982-1983), circa 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 6-14)
  - 16 Artists From the Printmaking Workshop (1983), 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fugitive Figure (1983), circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - OIA at Green Space: Sculpture (1983), 1982-circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17-20)
  - Paper Transformations (1983), circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 21-27)
  - Personal Expressionism (1983) (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - The Space Within (1983), 1982-circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 29-32)
  - Visual Artists Production Program (1983) (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Ward's Island Sculpture Garden (1983), 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
  - 16 Artists from the Printmaking Workshop (1984-1985), 1983-circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 36-39)
  - Hanging Loose (1984), circa 1983-circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 40-44)
  - Intuition and the Block Print (1984), circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 45-48)
  - Intuition and the Block Print (1984), circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Nature as Image (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
  - Personal Expressionism (1984), 1983-circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
  - Reverse Impressions (1984), circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
  - Sculpture Garden Two (1984), circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Ways of Wood (1984-1985), circa 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 14-22)
  - Brooklyn Waterfront Artists Coalition: 6th Annual Show (1985) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Constructions/ Obstructions (1985), circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 24-26)
  - Exhibit A (1985), circa 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 27-29)
  - Latitudes of Time (1985), circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 30-32)
  - Not Just Black and White (1985), circa 1984-circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 33-36)
  - The Razor Show (1985), 1984-circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 37-42)
  - Sculpture at Borough of Manhattan Community College (1985) (Box 8, Folder 43-48)
  - New Abstract Paintings (1986), circa 1986 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - New Abstract Paintings (1986), circa 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - OIA Salutes the Five Boroughs of New York City (1986), 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Pumpkin Festival Show (1986), circa 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Sculpture in Place (1986), circa 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - South Beach III (1986), circa 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9-14)
  - 10th Anniversary Show (1987), circa 1986-circa 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15-19)
  - Visions: Five Women Artists (1987), circa 1986-circa 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Candor of Form (1988), circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 21-24)
  - Gothic Mood (circa 1988) (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Installation: Six Views (1988), circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 26-29)
  - Snug Harbor Sculpture Festival (1988), circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 30-32)
  - Visual Impact (1988), circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Evolving Ethos: Paintings of the 80s (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Plane Into Form (1989), circa 1989 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Sculpture at Snug Harbor (1989), circa 1989 (Box 9, Folder 36-38)
  - Sculpture Island (1989), circa 1989 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Seven from the Street (1989), circa 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Topical Rain Forest (1989), circa 1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Image, Object Abstracted (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Exhibit at CUNY Graduate Center (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Issues of Humanity (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - JFK Airport Project (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Nature and Humanity (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - New Blood (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Points of Origin (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sculpture Garden II (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Show Your Metal (1990), circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Corner (the) Market (1991), circa 1991 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - CoVariants and Selections (1991), circa 1991 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
  - Geometric Wood Structures (1991), circa 1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Maps and Madness (1991), circa 1991 (Box 10, Folder 20-24)
  - OIA Salon Show (1991), circa 1991; 1 Floppy discs (Box 10, Folder 25-26)
  - Photographic Installations (1991) (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - An Unlikely Continuity (1991), circa 1991 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Urban Jungle (1991) (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Vanitas: Six Still Life Painters (1991) (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - 1+n=1: Installation Based Sculpture (1992), circa 1992 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Eye On Art (1992), circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
  - New Images in Stone (1992), circa 1992 (Box 10, Folder 34-35)
  - New Images in Stone (1992), circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Persistence of Subject (Selection) (1992), circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Spare Parts (1992), circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Real Paintings (1992), circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Refiguring the Form (1992), circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
  - Urban Alchemy (1992), circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Eye on Art (1993), 1992-circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 12-15)
  - Idio Cognito (1993), circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Infused with the Spirit (1993), circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - The Issue is Life (1993) (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Line-Up: At the Police Building (1993), circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Mindscapes: Abstraction and Experience (1993), circa 1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Object Lessons (1993), circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
  - OIA Salon Show (1993) (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Outdoor Sculpture (1993), circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 25-28)
  - Outdoor Sculpture (1993), 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Repair Work (1993, circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Selections from the Slide File (1993), circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Signs of Life (1993), circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - That Is a Hat (1993), circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Twisted State (1993), circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - VisionTelevision (circa 1990s) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Visual Aids (1993), 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Copier Art Show (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - The Critics' Choices (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Critics' Choice III (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Fire Without Gold: Six Photographers of Color (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Five Women Sculptors - Cinco Escultoras (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 15-20)
  - Landscapes: Seen and Remembered (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Making Evidence (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - OIA Salon Show (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 23-26)
  - Out of Line (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Paper Dolls (1994), circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Raw Materials (1994), circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Selections from the Slide File (1994), circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso (Chile) Biennial (1994), circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Behind the Eight Ball (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - By Design (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Curve Into Cursive (1995) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Expert Testimony: Russian Installations (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Friends, Family, Hearts and Flowers (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Internal Examination (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mindscapes, Abstraction, and Experience (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - OIA Art and Design Silent Auction (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - OIA Salon Show (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 12-17)
  - Paint and Circumstance (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Physical Sense (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Questioned and Embedded (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sculptors' Thinking Drawings (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Selections from the Slide File (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Six Views of New York: Cityscape Paintings (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Ten from the Salon (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Unwanted Figures of the Imagination (1995), circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - The Body Autonomous (1996), circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Darker Visions (1996), circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Fire Without Gold (1996), circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Landscapes (1996), circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Passages (1996), circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 30-31)
  - Passages (1996), circa 1996 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - Salon Shows (1996-1998), circa 1996-circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 5-7)
  - Saving the Scene (1996), circa 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Selections of Small Works from the Slide File (1996), circa 1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)